Literary Correspondence and Manuscripts Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Literary Correspondence and Manuscripts Collection
undated, 1929-1990.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
University of Connecticut. University of Connecticut Libraries.
1 linear foot.
MSS20010078
Artificial collection created by Special Collections prior to 1995.
History
The collection was created by Special Collections in the University of Connecticut Libraries prior to its merger with Historical Manuscripts and Archives in 1995.
Scope and Content
The collection contains single letters and literary manuscripts, or groups of fewer that ten (10) items, not part of a larger collection of papers. It includes manuscripts and letters by James Broughton, Andrei Codrescu, Edward Dahlberg, Robert Duncan, William Everson, Kenneth Koch, James Schuyler, Anne Waldman, and others.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of literary collections. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
People:
Broughton, James Richard, 1913-; Codrescu, Andrei, 1946-; Dahlberg, Edward, 1900-1977.; Duncan, Robert.; Everson, William, 1912-; Koch, Kenneth, 1925-; Schuyler, James.; Waldman, Anne, 1945-
Subjects:
universities and colleges--Connecticut.; Authors, American--Correspondence.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Manuscripts.; Notebooks.
Occupations:
Education.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
Unknown, probable purchases.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Collection, 1929-1990
  - Achebe, Chinua
    - The Flute, 197- (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - Bayes, Ronald H.
    - Note to Tove H. Rosado, 1985 (Box 1:, Folder 2-3)
  - Beltrametti, Franco, et. al.
    - West Coast Paria, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - Berge, Carol
    - Letter to D.A. Levy, [1965] (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Letter to Richard Elman, ca. 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - Blackburn, Paul
    - Letter to Joan Kelly, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - Branaman, Robert R.
    - Letter to Mary Beach and Claude Pelieu, 197- (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - Bremtford, William Hicks
    - Letter to editor of Everyman, 1929 (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - Broughton, James
    - The Loves of Lionel, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - Brownstein, Michael
    - Letter to Michael Lally, [1976] (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - Burns, Jim
    - Letter to Seamus Cooney, 1966, 1968 (Box 1:, Folder 12-13)
  - Carroll, Paul
    - Letter to David Ossman, 1962 (Box 1:, Folder 14)
  - Childs, J. Rives
    - Letters to Charles Lombardo, 1962-1963 (Box 1:, Folder 15)
  - Codrescu, Andrei
    - mad tall napoleon, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 16)
    - Letter to Michael Lally, 1975 (Box 1:, Folder 17)
    - Note to Carol [?], 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 18)
  - Collins, Jess
    - An Ouzel Plainting of a Stable-Loaf, 1956 (Box 1:, Folder 19)
  - Dahl, David
    - Letter to Clayton Eshleman, 1984 (Box 1:, Folder 20)
  - Dahlberg, Edward
    - Letter to John Cech, 1971-1972 (Box 1:, Folder 21-25)
    - Letter to Richard Schimmelpfeng, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
  - Doyle, Kirby
    - Drawing, 198- (Box 1:, Folder 27)
  - Duncan, Robert
    - Notebook, 1956 (Box 1:, Folder 28)
    - Structure of rime xxviii: in memoriam, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 29)
    - Note to Robert Ossorio, 1970 (Box 1:, Folder 30)
  - Einstein, Albert
    - Letters on behalf of Emergency Committee of Atomic Scientists, 1947-1948 (Box 1:, Folder 31)
  - Everson, William O.
    - Letters to Robert Hawley, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 32-38)
  - Gilbert, Gerry
    - Note to University of Connecticut Library, 1978 (Box 1:, Folder 39)
  - Ginsberg, Allen
    - Postcard to Derek Pell, 1971 (Box 1:, Folder 40)
  - Grady, Panna
    - Postcard to Alan Marlowe, 1969 (Box 1:, Folder 41)
  - Grelle, Leone Rice
    - Note, clipping and Pasture Crossing, 1973 (Box 1:, Folder 42)
  - Grenier, Robert
    - Four poems, ca. 1984 (Box 1:, Folder 43)
  - Heyen, William
    - Letters to Preston Beyer, 1979 (Box 1:, Folder 44)
  - Hillyer, Robert
    - Rosewood and Lullaby, undated (Box 1:, Folder 45)
  - Hirschman, Jack A.
    - Letter to Michael Lally, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 46)
  - Hollander, John
    - Letters to Lana L. Yurchyshyn, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 47-48)
    - Postcard to Lana L. Yurchyshyn, 1976 (Box 1:, Folder 49)
  - Hollo, Anselm
    - The Army of Unalterable Paws, 1989 (Box 1:, Folder 50)
    - [Poems], 1966 (Box 1:, Folder 51)
    - Smoke Writing, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 52)
    - Anselm's Dreams, 1972 (Box 1:, Folder 53)
  - Koch, Kenneth
    - Notebook: Poems 1952 (Box 1:, Folder 54)
    - Notebook: Sweden and New York, 1950-1951 (Box 1:, Folder 55)
      [includes Frank O'Hara fragment]
    - Notebook: The Tingley Machine..., 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 56)
    - The construction of Boston, 196- (Box 2:, Folder 57)
  - Lansing, Gerrit
    - Postcards to Gerard Malanga, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 58-59)
  - Levy, D.A.
    - Marealien 1-3, 1967 (Box 2:, Folder 60)
  - Lowenfels, Walter
    - Letter to James Roman, 1965 (Box 2:, Folder 61)
  - MacAdams, Lewis
    - The oldest living piano player comes to Bolinas, undated (Box 2:, Folder 62)
  - Malanga, Gerard
    - Card, letter, flyer, 1975-1990 (Box 2:, Folder 63)
  - Marlatt, Daphne
    - Letter to University of Connecticut Library, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 64)
  - Matson, Clive
    - Letters to Hettie Jones, 1966 (Box 2:, Folder 65-66)
  - Miller, Henry
    - Letter to Edward W. McTague, 1965-1966 (Box 2:, Folder 67-70)
  - Nichols, B.P.
    - Letter to Bob Cobbing, undated (Box 2:, Folder 71)
  - Padgett, Ron
    - The bunchberries, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 72)
    - Letter to Richard Schimmelpfeng, 1981 (Box 2:, Folder 73)
  - Richmond, Steve
    - Letter to “Loss”, 1983 (Box 2:, Folder 74)
  - Rosenberg, Samuel
    - Letter to Donald Sutherland, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 75)
  - Prince, F.T.
    - Letters to Peter Russell, 1957-1960 (Box 2:, Folder 76)
  - Rukyser, Muriel
    - Letter to Nancy Perrac, 1943 (Box 2:, Folder 77)
  - Schuyler, James
    - Notebook, 1971 (Box 2:, Folder 78)
    - Notebook, 1971 July - August (Box 2:, Folder 79)
    - Poem: “a plane passes overhead...”, 1979 (Box 2:, Folder 80)
  - Smith, Alexander
    - A Woman, Men, and three Clouds, ca. 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 81)
  - Snow, Wilbert
    - Letters to Kenneth Stuart, 1971, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 82-83)
  - Spender, Stephen
    - Letter to Lana L. Yurchyshyn, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 84)
    - Cyril Connolly, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 85)
    - From my Diary, ca. 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 86)
    - Letter to Lana L. Yurchyshyn, 1976 (Box 2:, Folder 87)
  - Stein, Charles
    - Photograph with J. Akeroyd, 1973 (Box 2:, Folder 88)
    - Letter to Norman Stevens, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 105)
  - Swann, Brian
    - Note to Richard Schimmlpfeng, 1985 (Box 2:, Folder 89)
  - Vas Dias, Robert
    - Letter to John Cooley, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 90)
  - Waldman, Anne
    - Instinctive Actions!, 1969 (Box 2:, Folder 91)
    - Postcards and letters to Jim Carroll, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 92-94)
    - Letter to Andrew Wylie and Victor Bockris, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 95)
    - Letter to Jim Carroll, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 96-98)
  - Weaver, Ken
    - Nipple often Collapses with note to Mary Beach and Claude Pelieu, undated (Box 2:, Folder 99)
  - Weissner, Carl
    - Letters to Claude Pelieu and March Beach, 1972-1974 (Box 2:, Folder 100)
    - Le Strp-Tease Surprise, 1974 (Box 2:, Folder 101)
  - Williams, Jonathan
    - Letters to Hank B. Chapin, 1962-1963 (Box 2:, Folder 102-103)
  - Wright, Charles
    - Letter to Lana L. Yurchyshyn, 1975 (Box 2:, Folder 104)